var chapters = [
  //   { chapter: 1, title: "Foreign Trade" },
  //   { chapter: 2, title: "Exchange Control in India" },
  //   { chapter: 3, title: "Asian Clearing Union , ECU & LIBOR" },
  //   { chapter: 4, title: "Free Trade Zones & OBU" },
  //   { chapter: 5, title: "International Commercial Terms - INCOTERMS" },
  //   { chapter: 6, title: "Foreign Trade -Documents" },
  //   { chapter: 7, title: "Import Trade -Guidelines" },
  //   { chapter: 8, title: "Import Trade -Regulations" },
  //   { chapter: 9, title: "Documaentary credit-Method of financing Import" },
  {
    chapter: 10,
    title:
      "Establishment of LC, Import bills under LC, Collection and other import regulations",
  },
  { chapter: 11, title: "Other Methods of Import Financing" },
  { chapter: 12, title: "Export Control -Guidelines" },
  { chapter: 13, title: "Export-Obligations and Role of AD Banks" },
  { chapter: 14, title: "Export Finance- Pre shipment Finance in Rupee" },
  {
    chapter: 15,
    title: "Export Finance- Pre shipment Finance in Foreign Currency",
  },
  { chapter: 16, title: "Export Finance- Post shipment Finance in Rupee" },
  {
    chapter: 17,
    title: "Export Finance- Post shipment Finance in Foreign Currency",
  },
  { chapter: 18, title: "Project Export and export under deferred payment" },
  { chapter: 19, title: "Export Promotion Incentives" },
  { chapter: 20, title: "ECGC-Role in Export promotion" },
  { chapter: 21, title: "Guarantees for Import and export" },
  { chapter: 22, title: "Export Promotion Measures" },
  { chapter: 23, title: "Foreign Trade Policy" },
];

var allQuestionAnswers = [
  {
    question:
      "Before taking decision on the application, the banker should check up the ………...of the applicant.",
    options: ["creditworthiness ", "address", "accounts ", "IEC code"],
    answer: "creditworthiness ",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under incoterms…….contract the insurance is provided by the importer, the banker in order to protect the interest of the bank should see to it that the insurance cover is duly obtained by the customer.",
    options: ["FOB  ", "FOB or C& F ", "CIF", "C &F"],
    answer: "FOB or C& F ",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Import bills under the FEDAI rule include…………….",
    options: [
      "Advance bills \n",
      "Bills drawn under as banks own LC ",
      "Plain collection items\n",
      " Advance bills, Bills drawn under as banks own LC and \nPlain collection items\n",
    ],
    answer:
      " Advance bills, Bills drawn under as banks own LC and \nPlain collection items\n",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Bill of lading is submitted within ………..from the date of shipment, if no specific time is between the date of issue and expiry of L/C",
    options: [" 3 days f", "7 days ", "21days f", "30 days"],
    answer: "21days f",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Date of receipt of Import documents in case of import bills under LC is very important, so documents must be …………..",
    options: [
      "date sealed and time marked. ",
      "kept in security vault",
      "kept in drawer ",
      "handed over to officer",
    ],
    answer: "date sealed and time marked. ",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Within ………...acceptance or rejection is required to convey to Remitting Bank?",
    options: [
      "3 banking day’s ",
      "5 banking day’s ",
      "7 banking day’s ",
      "21 banking day’s ",
    ],
    answer: "5 banking day’s ",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "On …………. bill should be delinked",
    options: [" 3rd day", "5 th day", "10th day", "7th  day "],
    answer: "10th day",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The payment to the overseas supplier should be made in a currency or through an account appropriate to the ……………..",
    options: [
      "country of origin of the goods ",
      " country from which they may be shipped.",
      "country of origin of the goods irrespective of the country from which they may be shipped.",
      "as per the instruction of supplier of goods ",
    ],
    answer:
      "country of origin of the goods irrespective of the country from which they may be shipped.",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In terms of the extant regulations, remittances against imports should be completed not later than………... from the date of shipment",
    options: [
      " six months",
      " nine  months",
      " twelve months",
      " fifteen months",
    ],
    answer: " six months",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "bank may allow payment of interest on usance bills or overdue interest for a period of…………..from the date of shipment at the rate prescribed for trade credit from time to time",
    options: [
      " less than three months  ",
      " less than three years ",
      " less than one  years ",
      " less than five  years ",
    ],
    answer: " less than three years ",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In case of pre-payment of usance import bills, remittances may be made only after reducing the proportionate interest for the unexpired portion of usance at the rate …………, whichever is applicable",
    options: [
      "at which interest has been claimed ",
      "LIBOR of the currency in which the goods have been invoiced",
      "at which interest has been claimed or LIBOR of the currency in which the goods have been invoiced",
      "LIBOR + 100 bps",
    ],
    answer:
      "at which interest has been claimed or LIBOR of the currency in which the goods have been invoiced",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "When the licence is fully utilised, or when the balance not yet utilised is so significant that the licence cannot be further utilised, the exchange control copy, duly endorsed, should be .............. for remittance made against it.",
    options: [
      "surrendered to the Reserve Bank of India",
      "surrendered to  authorised dealer bank, ",
      "surrendered to the Reserve Bank of India / authorised dealer bank, ",
      "surrendered to the overseas bank, ",
    ],
    answer:
      "surrendered to the Reserve Bank of India / authorised dealer bank, ",
    chapter: 10,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Buyer’s Credit refers to loans for payment of imports into India arranged on behalf of the importer through an overseas bank. Based on letter of undertaking of …….credits the Nostro of the importer’s bank.",
    options: [
      "Importer’s bank or  overseas bank  ",
      "Importer’s bank",
      " overseas bank ",
      "Reserve Bank of India ",
    ],
    answer: "Importer’s bank or  overseas bank  ",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Buyer’s Credit refers to loans for payment of imports into India arranged on behalf of the importer through an overseas bank. Based on letter of undertaking of …….credits the Nostro of the importer’s bank.",
    options: [
      "Importer’s bank or  overseas bank  ",
      "Importer’s bank",
      " overseas bank ",
      "Reserve Bank of India ",
    ],
    answer: "Importer’s bank or  overseas bank  ",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the benefit of buyer’s credit for the importer?",
    options: [
      "The exporter gets paid on due date; whereas importer gets extended date for making an import payment as per the cash flows",
      "importer gets extended date for making an import payment as per the cash flows",
      "cheaper credit ",
      "easy funds ",
    ],
    answer:
      "importer gets extended date for making an import payment as per the cash flows",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Maximum Amount Per transaction of buyers credit should not exceed………..:",
    options: ["$20 Million", "$10Million", "$25 Million", "$50 Million"],
    answer: "$20 Million",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Buyers credit Maximum Maturity in case of import of non-capital goods is ……….. from the date of shipment",
    options: ["upto 1 year", "upto 3 year", "upto 5 year", "upto 6 months"],
    answer: "upto 1 year",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "AD banks are permitted to issue…………….in favour of overseas supplier, bank and financial institution, up to USD 20 million per transaction for a period up to one year for import of all non-capital goods permissible under Foreign Trade Policy",
    options: [
      " Letters of Credit /guarantees/Letter of Undertaking (LoU) /Letter of Comfort (LoC) ",
      " Letter of guarantees ",
      "Letter of Undertaking (LoU) ",
      "Letter of Comfort (LoC)",
    ],
    answer:
      " Letters of Credit /guarantees/Letter of Undertaking (LoU) /Letter of Comfort (LoC) ",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Forfeiting covers risk of………….",
    options: [
      "Sovereign Risk\n \n",
      " Commercial Banks \n",
      "Sovereign Risk, Commercial Banks  and Prime corporate \n",
      "Prime corporate ",
    ],
    answer: "Sovereign Risk, Commercial Banks  and Prime corporate \n",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exchange of goods or services directly for other goods or services without the use of money as means of purchase or payment is called as………",
    options: ["Barter ", "Switch Trading ", "Counter purchase ", "offset "],
    answer: "Barter ",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Practice in which one company sells to another its obligation to make a purchase in a given country is called as……..",
    options: [
      "Switch trading",
      "Barter ",
      "counter purchase",
      "buy Back ",
      "offset ",
    ],
    answer: "Switch trading",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Sale of goods and services to one company in other country by a company that promises to make a future purchase of a specific product from the same company in that country is called as ………",
    options: [
      "barter ",
      "counter purchase",
      "Switch Trading ",
      "buy Back ",
      "offset ",
    ],
    answer: "counter purchase",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Agreement by one nation to buy a product from another, subject to the purchase of some or all of the components and raw materials from the buyer of the finished product, or the assembly of such product in the buyer nation is called as………..",
    options: ["Barter ", "Switch Trading ", "Counter purchase ", "offset "],
    answer: "offset ",
    chapter: 11,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Export trade is regulated by the ……………………",
    options: [
      "Directorate General of Foreign Trade (DGFT) and its regional offices",
      "Reserve and its regional offices",
      "AD banks and its controling offices",
      "FEDAI",
    ],
    answer:
      "Directorate General of Foreign Trade (DGFT) and its regional offices",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "All export contracts and invoices shall be denominated either in freely convertible currency or Indian rupees but export proceeds shall be realized in ………………..",
    options: [
      "Indian Rupees ",
      "freely convertible currency",
      "US Dollar",
      "Any foreign currency",
    ],
    answer: "freely convertible currency",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The period of realization and repatriation of export proceeds shall be……….from the date of export for all exporters",
    options: [
      " six  months ",
      " nine months ",
      " twelve  months ",
      "fifteen months ",
    ],
    answer: " nine months ",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "For goods exported to a warehouse established outside India, the proceeds shall be realized within………    from the date of shipment of goods",
    options: [
      " six  months ",
      " nine months ",
      " twelve  months ",
      "fifteen months ",
    ],
    answer: "fifteen months ",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "OPGSP facility shall only be available for export of goods and services of value not exceeding…………..",
    options: [" USD 10,000", " USD 5,000", " USD 25,000", " USD 2,000"],
    answer: " USD 10,000",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under OPGSPThe balances held in the NOSTRO collection account shall be repatriated and credited to the respective exporter's account with a bank in India immediately on receipt of the confirmation from the importer and, in no case, later than ............",
    options: ["five days", "seven days", "twenty one  days", "thirty days"],
    answer: "seven days",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "A unit located in a Special Economic Zone (SEZ) may open, hold and maintain a ………...with an AD Category – I bank in India",
    options: [
      "Foreign Currency Account ",
      "EEFC account ",
      "DDA account",
      "FCNR (B) account",
    ],
    answer: "Foreign Currency Account ",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "All categories of foreign exchange earners are allowed to credit 100% of their foreign exchange earnings to their ………..",
    options: [
      "Foreign Currency Account ",
      "EEFC account ",
      "DDA account",
      "FCNR (B) account",
    ],
    answer: "EEFC account ",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who will consider awarding post-award approvals without any monetary limit and permit subsequent changes in the terms of post award approval within the relevant FEMA guidelines / regulations?.",
    options: [
      "AD banks ",
      " Exim Bank",
      "AD banks / Exim Bank",
      "Reserve Bank ",
    ],
    answer: "AD banks / Exim Bank",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "After the documents have been negotiated / sent for collection, the AD shall report the transaction through …………... to the Reserve Bank and retain the documents at their end.",
    options: ["IDPMS", "FETERS ", "EDPMS", "Special reporting"],
    answer: "EDPMS",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Postal Authorities shall allow export of goods by post only if the original copy of the EDF has been countersigned by……………..",
    options: [" an AD Bank ", "Customs ", "RBI ", "Exporter"],
    answer: " an AD Bank ",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In case of Mid-sea trans-shipment of catch by deep sea fishing vessels,exporters may submit the EDF, duly signed by the …………………",
    options: [
      "Master of the vessel in lieu of Custom certification",
      "nearest of customs office ",
      "vessel owner ",
      "exporter ",
    ],
    answer: "Master of the vessel in lieu of Custom certification",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "When part of a shipment covered by an EDF already filed with Customs is short-shipped, the exporter must …………... in the form and manner prescribed",
    options: [
      "give notice of short-shipment to the RBI",
      "give notice of short-shipment to the AD Bank ",
      "give notice of short-shipment to the Customs",
      "give notice of short-shipment to the overseas bank",
    ],
    answer: "give notice of short-shipment to the Customs",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Where a shipment has been entirely shut out and there is delay in making arrangements to re-ship, the exporter will ………………….in the form and manner prescribed",
    options: [
      "give notice in duplicate to the Customs ",
      "give notice in duplicate to the RBI ",
      "give notice in duplicate to the AD Bank",
      "give notice in duplicate to the overseas buyer",
    ],
    answer: "give notice in duplicate to the Customs ",
    chapter: 12,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Banks may consider requests for grant of EDF waiver from exporters for export of goods free of cost, for export promotion up to 2 per cent of the average annual exports of the applicant during the preceding three financial years subject to a ceiling of .",
    options: ["Rs.5 lakhs", "Rs.10 lakhs", "Rs.15 lakhs", "Rs.25 lakhs"],
    answer: "Rs.5 lakhs",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exports of goods not involving any foreign exchange transaction directly or indirectly requires the waiver of EDF procedure from the ……………….",
    options: ["AD Bank ", "Overseas bank ", "RBI ", "EXIM bank"],
    answer: "RBI ",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "where an exporter receives advance payment , from a buyer outside India, the exporter shall be under an obligation to ensure that the shipment of goods is made within ……….from the date of receipt of advance payment",
    options: ["one year ", "9 months  ", "3 year ", "18 months  "],
    answer: "one year ",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The rate of interest, if any, payable on the advance payment should not exceed London Inter-Bank Offered Rate (LIBOR) + 100 basis points",
    options: [
      "London Inter-Bank Offered Rate (LIBOR) ",
      "London Inter-Bank Offered Rate (LIBOR) + 100 basis points",
      "London Inter-Bank Offered Rate (LIBOR) + 150 basis points",
      "London Inter-Bank Offered Rate (LIBOR) + 250 basis points",
    ],
    answer: "London Inter-Bank Offered Rate (LIBOR) + 100 basis points",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Banks will have to report all the inward remittances including advance as well as old outstanding inward remittances received for export of goods/ software to …………………….",
    options: ["EDPMS", "IDPMS", "FETERS", "XOS"],
    answer: "EDPMS",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In case of re-export of unsold rough diamonds imported on free of cost basis at SNZ, the unsold rough diamonds, when re-exported from the SNZ without entering the Domestic Tariff Area (DTA), ……….",
    options: [
      "Require to complete EDF formality",
      "do not require any EDF formality",
      "No obbligation to complete formality",
      "declaration by exporter is enough ",
    ],
    answer: "do not require any EDF formality",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "At the time of setting up of the office, banks may allow remittances towards initial expenses up to ......... of the average annual sales/income or turnover during the last two financial years or up to twenty-five per cent of the net worth, whichever is h",
    options: [
      "fifteen per cent",
      "ten per cent ",
      "twenty five percent",
      "five percent",
    ],
    answer: "fifteen per cent",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In case the goods are exported on consignment basis, …………..must be arranged in India",
    options: [
      "freight and marine insurance ",
      "freight ",
      " marine insurance ",
      "freight or  marine insurance ",
    ],
    answer: "freight and marine insurance ",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "After goods have been shipped, and if they are to be transferred to a buyer other than the original buyer in the event of default by the latter, provided the reduction in value, if any, involved does not exceed ………….. of the invoice value",
    options: ["25 per cent", "10 per cent", "15 per cent", "5 per cent"],
    answer: "25 per cent",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "While considering extension beyond one year from the date of export, the total outstanding of the exporter does not exceed …………..., whichever is higher",
    options: [
      "USD one million",
      " 10 per cent of the average export realizations ",
      " USD one million or 10 per cent of the average export realizations during the preceding three financial years",
      " USD ten million or 10 per cent of the average export realizations during the preceding three financial years",
    ],
    answer:
      " USD one million or 10 per cent of the average export realizations during the preceding three financial years",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The netting off of export receivables against import payments is in respect of the same Indian entity and the overseas buyer / supplier (bilateral netting) and the netting may be done as on ………..of the unit in SEZ.",
    options: [
      "the date of balance sheet ",
      "the date of Request ",
      "the date of balance sheet of overseas entity ",
      "the date of balance sheet entity outside SEZ ",
    ],
    answer: "the date of balance sheet ",
    chapter: 13,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Financial assistance extended to the exporters, from the date of receipt of export order till the date of shipment, falls within the scope of ………",
    options: [
      "Export finance. ",
      "pre-shipment finance. ",
      "post-shipment finance. ",
      "general Finance",
    ],
    answer: "pre-shipment finance. ",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Pre-shipment credit is a …………….extended to a registered exporter in anticipation of his exporting the goods to an importer in a foreign country",
    options: [
      "working capital facility ",
      "Term loan facility ",
      "Finance  facility ",
      "General Finance facility ",
    ],
    answer: "working capital facility ",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The purpose of advance is to enable the exporter to ………….. etc. or for purchase of ready goods for export",
    options: [
      "purchase raw material",
      "manufacturing, processing, packing, transporting, warehousing",
      "purchase raw material, its manufacturing, processing, packing, transporting, warehousing",
      " processing, packing, transporting, warehousing",
    ],
    answer:
      "purchase raw material, its manufacturing, processing, packing, transporting, warehousing",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Generally packing credit facility can be granted to an exporter on the basis of…………….opened in his favour or confirmed and irrevocable order for export of goods",
    options: [
      " letter of credit ",
      "local purchase order",
      "supply order",
      "Domestic LC ",
    ],
    answer: " letter of credit ",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In cases where manufacture/supplier of goods and exporter of goods are two different parties, the packing credit loan can be ………. and amount sanctioned.",
    options: [
      "Supplier ",
      "manufacture",
      "shared between supplier and manufacturer within the overall time limit",
      "granted seperatly",
    ],
    answer:
      "shared between supplier and manufacturer within the overall time limit",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "If oreder is over phone or telex/fax an undertaking to the effect that original export order would be produced as soon as it is received but within a maximum period of ……………….should be obtained",
    options: ["30 days ", "90 days ", "15 days ", "7 days "],
    answer: "30 days ",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "The packing credit limit is assessed on the basis of ……….",
    options: [
      "estimated projected export orders to be executed by the exporter",
      "as per request of the exporter",
      "as stated in LC ",
      "as stated in Order",
    ],
    answer: "estimated projected export orders to be executed by the exporter",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The advance in excess of the export order is required to be adjusted either in cash or by sale of residual by-product oil within a period not exceeding ……………..from the date of advance.",
    options: ["7 days ", "15 days ", "30 days ", "on due date "],
    answer: "30 days ",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Rupee Pre-shipment Credit granted to Construction Contractorsshould be adjusted within …………... from the date of advance by negotiation of bills relating to the contract or by remittances received from abroad in respect of the contract executed abroad.",
    options: ["360days", "365 days", "180 days", "90 days"],
    answer: "365 days",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Banks are permitted to grant packing credit advance to exporters of HPS groundnut and deoiled / defatted cakes to the extent of the …………….",
    options: [
      "value of raw materials required ",
      "less than value of raw materials required ",
      "value of raw materials required even though the value thereof exceeds the value of the export order",
      "as requested in the absence of order",
    ],
    answer:
      "value of raw materials required even though the value thereof exceeds the value of the export order",
    chapter: 14,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Post-shipment finance can be allowed as ……………...",
    options: [
      "Purchase of export bills",
      "Discount of export bills",
      "Negotiation of export bills",
      "Purchase/Discount Negotiation of export bills",
    ],
    answer: "Purchase/Discount Negotiation of export bills",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In case of deemed exports, the finance is extended to the ……………………",
    options: [
      "Buyer of the goods ",
      "Exporter of goods ",
      "supplier of goods.",
      "sub supplier of goods ",
    ],
    answer: "supplier of goods.",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "As per exchange control regulations, for cash exports it can be for a maximum period of ………..from the date of shipment",
    options: ["90 days ", "270 days ", "180 days ", "360 days "],
    answer: "180 days ",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In case of usance bills, credit can be granted for a maximum duration of 180 days from the date of shipment ………...and grace period if any.",
    options: [
      "Inclusive of Normal Transit Period (NTP)",
      "Normal Transit Period (NTP)",
      "Excluding Normal Transit Period (NTP)",
      "actual due date",
    ],
    answer: "Normal Transit Period (NTP)",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "At present Normal Transit period for purpose of all bills in foreign currency is ………..",
    options: ["29 days", "25 days", "30 days", "21 days"],
    answer: "25 days",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "RBI has been allowing in deserving cases, on application by individual exporters with satisfactory track record, a longer period upto …………. from the date of shipment for realization of proceeds when goods are sent on consignement basis.",
    options: ["6 months", "9 months", "12 months", "15 months"],
    answer: "12 months",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In case of Exports through the Warehouse–cum-Display Centres abroad, realisation of export proceeds has been fixed upto……….. months from the date of shipment.",
    options: ["6 months", "9 months", "12 months", "15 months"],
    answer: "15 months",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Banks may consider granting advances against undrawn balances at concessional rate of interest based on their commercial judgement and the track record of the buyer. Such advances are, however, eligible for concessional rate of interest for a maximum peri",
    options: ["30 days ", "45 days ", "90 days ", "180 days "],
    answer: "90 days ",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Where the retention money is payable within a period of …………….from the date of shipment, according to the terms of the contract, banks should charge prescribed rate of interest upto a maximum period of 90 days.",
    options: ["one year ", "as per agreement", "three years ", "five  year "],
    answer: "one year ",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Whole Turnover Post-shipment Guarantee Scheme of the Export Credit Guarantee Corporation of India Ltd. (ECGC) provides protection to ……………. against non-payment of post-shipment credit by exporters",
    options: ["Exporter ", "shipper ", "Bank ", "sub supplier"],
    answer: "Bank ",
    chapter: 16,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Banks may utilise the foreign exchange resources available with them in…………... to discount usance bills and retain them in their portfolio without resorting to rediscounting",
    options: [
      " Exchange Earners Foreign Currency Accounts (EEFC), ",
      " Exchange Earners Foreign Currency Accounts (EEFC), Resident Foreign Currency Accounts (RFC),",
      " Exchange Earners Foreign Currency Accounts (EEFC), Resident Foreign Currency Accounts (RFC), Foreign Currency (Non-Resident) Accounts (Banks) Scheme,",
      ", Foreign Currency (Non-Resident) Accounts (Banks) Scheme,",
    ],
    answer:
      " Exchange Earners Foreign Currency Accounts (EEFC), Resident Foreign Currency Accounts (RFC), Foreign Currency (Non-Resident) Accounts (Banks) Scheme,",
    chapter: 17,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Post shipment Finance in Foreign Currency  Scheme will cover mainly export bills with usance period upto ……………….from the date of shipment",
    options: ["90 days ", "180 days ", "270 days ", "360 days "],
    answer: "180 days ",
    chapter: 17,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Banks may avail of lines of credit from other banks in India if they are not in a position to raise loans from abroad on their own or they do not have branches abroad, subject to the condition that ultimate cost to the exporter should not exceed …………..",
    options: [
      "100 basis points ",
      "100 basis points ",
      "150 basis points ",
      "150 basis points ",
      "250 basis points ",
      "250 basis points ",
      "350 basis points ",
      "350 basis points ",
    ],
    answer: "350 basis points ",
    chapter: 17,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Bills rediscounted ‘with recourse’ in the domestic market could get reflected only in the case of the first bank discounting the bills as that bank alone will have ………….. and the bank rediscounting will not reckon the amount as export credit.",
    options: [
      "recourse to the exporter",
      "without recourse to the exporter",
      "recourse to the Bank ",
      "recourse to the financing institutions",
    ],
    answer: "recourse to the exporter",
    chapter: 17,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Direct discounting of export bills by exporters with overseas bank and/or any other agency will be done only through the…………….",
    options: [
      "Designated branch of the bank",
      "any branch of the bank ",
      "within the country ",
      "through correspondent bank",
    ],
    answer: "Designated branch of the bank",
    chapter: 17,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Banks may avail of ……………….. in India if they are not in a position to raise loans from abroad on their own or they do not have branches abroad, subject to the condition that ultimate cost to the exporter should not exceed 350 basis points",
    options: [
      "lines of credit from other banks",
      "lines of credit from overseas banks",
      "lines of credit from other Financial istitutions ",
      "lines of credit from other Financial istitutions from abroad",
    ],
    answer: "lines of credit from other banks",
    chapter: 17,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Banks may avail of lines of credit from other banks in India if they are not in a position to raise loans from abroad on their own or they do not have branches abroad, subject to the condition that ultimate cost to the exporter should not exceed …………..",
    options: [
      "100 basis points ",
      "100 basis points ",
      "150 basis points ",
      "150 basis points ",
      "250 basis points ",
      "250 basis points ",
      "350 basis points ",
      "350 basis points ",
    ],
    answer: "350 basis points ",
    chapter: 17,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "It is recognised that it will be difficult to get ‘without recourse’ facility from abroad under BAF or any other facility. Therefore, the bills may be rediscounted ‘with recourse’. However, if an AD is in a position to arrange ....................facility",
    options: [
      "without recourse ",
      "with recourse ",
      " recourse to Exporter",
      "without recourse to exporters",
    ],
    answer: "without recourse ",
    chapter: 17,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Commercial banks who are authorised dealers in foreign exchange in India, can provide in principle clearance for contracts valued upto …………..",
    options: [
      "Rs.5 crores",
      "Rs.5 crores",
      "Rs.10 crores",
      "Rs.10 crores",
      "Rs.15 crores",
      "Rs.15 crores",
      "Rs.25 crores",
      "Rs.25 crores",
    ],
    answer: "Rs.25 crores",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "EXIM bank is empowered to give clearances for contracts of value of above Rs.25 crores and upto………………..",
    options: [
      " Rs. 50 crores. ",
      " Rs. 50 crores. ",
      " Rs. 100 crores. ",
      " Rs. 100 crores. ",
      " Rs. 200 crores. ",
      " Rs. 200 crores. ",
      " Rs. 500 crores. ",
      " Rs. 500 crores. ",
    ],
    answer: " Rs. 100 crores. ",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Commercial banks who are authorised dealers in foreign exchange in India, can provide in principle clearance for contracts valued upto …………..",
    options: [
      "Rs.5 crores",
      "Rs.5 crores",
      "Rs.10 crores",
      "Rs.10 crores",
      "Rs.15 crores",
      "Rs.15 crores",
      "Rs.25 crores",
      "Rs.25 crores",
    ],
    answer: "Rs.25 crores",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "EXIM bank is empowered to give clearances for contracts of value of above Rs.25 crores and upto………………..",
    options: [
      " Rs. 50 crores. ",
      " Rs. 50 crores. ",
      " Rs. 100 crores. ",
      " Rs. 100 crores. ",
      " Rs. 200 crores. ",
      " Rs. 200 crores. ",
      " Rs. 500 crores. ",
      " Rs. 500 crores. ",
    ],
    answer: " Rs. 100 crores. ",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "A ………….. considers proposals of contracts of value beyond Rs. 100 crores.",
    options: ["AD Bank ", "EXIM Bank ", "working group", "RBI "],
    answer: "working group",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The projects involving supply of equipment along with related services like design, detailed engineering, civil construction, erection and commissioning of plants, etc. is called as …………..",
    options: [
      "Project Exports",
      "Services export ",
      "Turnkey project ",
      "Construction project",
    ],
    answer: "Turnkey project ",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Contracts for export of goods on deferred payment terms may be financed …………..",
    options: [
      "under supplier’s credit ",
      "under buyer’s credit",
      "either under supplier’s credit or buyer’s credit",
      "Loan ",
    ],
    answer: "either under supplier’s credit or buyer’s credit",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Consumer durables and miscellaneous engineering goods should ordinarily be exported on cash terms and   factor such as ….…..constitute the criteria for determining the overall terms of credit.",
    options: [
      "anticipated life of the goods to be exported, extent of foreign competition, nature of the foreign market and the contract value ",
      " extent of foreign competition, nature of the foreign market and the contract value ",
      " nature of the foreign market and the contract value ",
      " contract value ",
    ],
    answer:
      "anticipated life of the goods to be exported, extent of foreign competition, nature of the foreign market and the contract value ",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Moratorium or grace period applicable to repayment of principal (and not to payment of interest) should not exceed …………….. in respect of export of capital or producer goods",
    options: ["3 years", "1 year", " 6 months ", "9 months "],
    answer: "1 year",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Ordinarily, down payment together with advance payment or mobilisation advance should not be less than ……of the contract value",
    options: ["5 per cent ", "10 per cent ", "15 per cent ", "25 per cent "],
    answer: "15 per cent ",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Bridge finance required for meeting temporary shortfalls in working capital should not normally exceed ………… of the contract value.",
    options: ["5 per cent ", "10 per cent ", "15 per cent ", "25 per cent "],
    answer: "25 per cent ",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Authorised dealers / Exim Bank may grant post-award clearance to the project proposal ……………",
    options: [
      "without any monetary limit. ",
      "with  monetary limit. ",
      "within power delegated",
      "as per application ",
    ],
    answer: "without any monetary limit. ",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The ………... will be accountable to the various authorities in India for compliance with the requirements laid down by them and will at the same time be equally responsible to the overseas buyer for proper and timely completion of the contract",
    options: [
      "prime contractor",
      "prime contractor",
      "sub contractor ",
      "sub contractor ",
      "sub contractor in India ",
      "sub contractor in India ",
      "sub contractor in overseas country",
      "sub contractor in overseas country",
    ],
    answer: "prime contractor",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exporters desiring to submit bids for execution of projects abroad including service contract may furnish their own Corporate Guarantee in lieu of Bid Bond Guarantee, if they so desire, subject to the condition that the amount of such guarantee shall not",
    options: ["5 per cent ", "10 per cent", "15 per cent", "25 per cent"],
    answer: "5 per cent ",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The transfer of surplus funds of completed overseas project to another ongoing project of the same project exporter is ............... since such surplus becomes repatriable to India as soon as the project is completed and provisional completion certifica",
    options: [
      "Permitted ",
      "not permitted",
      "hold in account ",
      "Reptriate to India",
    ],
    answer: "not permitted",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The ………... will be accountable to the various authorities in India for compliance with the requirements laid down by them and will at the same time be equally responsible to the overseas buyer for proper and timely completion of the contract",
    options: [
      "prime contractor",
      "prime contractor",
      "sub contractor ",
      "sub contractor ",
      "sub contractor in India ",
      "sub contractor in India ",
      "sub contractor in overseas country",
      "sub contractor in overseas country",
    ],
    answer: "prime contractor",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Where exporters executing turnkey/civil construction /service contracts abroad are granted an approval by the approving authority to raise foreign currency loans /overdrafts abroad against counter guarantees of their ............ for bridging temporary sh",
    options: [
      "bankers in India,",
      "overseas banker ",
      "Financial institutions in India ",
      "Financial institutions overseas ",
    ],
    answer: "bankers in India,",
    chapter: 18,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "ASIDE scheme provides an outlay for …………... which is distributed among the States, inter-alia, on the basis of the States' export performance in the previous year",
    options: [
      "development of Import  infrastructure",
      "development of export infrastructure",
      "development of Trade infrastructure",
      "development of Manufacturing export infrastructure",
    ],
    answer: "development of export infrastructure",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "RBI as the Monetary Authority aims to maintain ……………... it seeks to facilitate external trade and payment and promote orderly development and maintenance of foreign exchange market in India",
    options: [
      "price stability",
      "ensure adequate flow of credit to productive sectors ",
      "price stability and ensure adequate flow of credit to productive sectors and being the Manager of Foreign Exchange,",
      " ensure adequate flow of credit to productive sectors and being the Manager of Foreign Exchange,",
    ],
    answer:
      "price stability and ensure adequate flow of credit to productive sectors and being the Manager of Foreign Exchange,",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The RBI has granted freedom to the Banks to get funds from abroad without any limit for exclusively for the purpose of granting………",
    options: [
      "export credit in Indian Rupee ",
      "export credit in foreign currency",
      "export credit in USD ",
      "Import Credit in foreign currency",
    ],
    answer: "export credit in foreign currency",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exim Bank lays special emphasis on ………..to overseas entities, national governments, regional financial institutions and commercial banks.",
    options: [
      "extension of Lines of Credit (LOCs) ",
      "granting post shipment Finance",
      "granting foreign currency Loan ",
      "Foreign currency loan syndication",
    ],
    answer: "extension of Lines of Credit (LOCs) ",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exim Bank also extends ……………. to finance and promote country’s exports",
    options: [
      "Buyer’s credit and Supplier’s credit",
      "Buyer’s credit or  Supplier’s credit",
      "Preshipment credi",
      "Loan for post shipment ",
    ],
    answer: "Buyer’s credit and Supplier’s credit",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The EXIM Bank has introduced a new lending programme to finance research and development activities of ………...",
    options: [
      "SEZ units",
      "100 percent export-oriented companies.",
      "export-oriented companies.",
      "EHTP units",
    ],
    answer: "export-oriented companies.",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Buyer's Credit is extended by EXIM bank  to a foreign project company that intends to …………….to an Indian project exporter",
    options: [
      "participate in  the project execution ",
      "in the process of execution of project ",
      "award the project execution ",
      "provide services ",
    ],
    answer: "participate in  the project execution ",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exim Bank has arranged for a credit line from the Asian Development Bank (ADB) for providing foreign currency term loans to the………….borrowers in certain specific lagging states of India",
    options: ["Agriculture ", " MSME ", "EOU ", "SEZ Units"],
    answer: " MSME ",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Commercial Banks, in their turn, play an important part of promoting exports. This role consist primary in providing ……………..",
    options: [
      "export credits to exporters and / or furnishing guarantees on behalf of Exporters.   ",
      "export credits to exporters ",
      " furnishing guarantees on behalf of Exporters.   ",
      "all foreign exchange needs of exporter",
    ],
    answer:
      "export credits to exporters and / or furnishing guarantees on behalf of Exporters.   ",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exports of notified goods of FOB value upto ………..per consignment, through courier or foreign post office using e-commerce shall be entitled for MEIS benefit.",
    options: ["Rs 25, 000 ", "Rs 15, 000 ", "Rs 10, 000 ", "Rs 5, 000 "],
    answer: "Rs 25, 000 ",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a bid to arrest the decline in exports, the Central government has announced an interest equalisation scheme on pre and post shipment rupee export credit with effect from 1st April, 2015 for ……………..",
    options: ["one year.", "two  years.", "three years.", "five years."],
    answer: "five years.",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The rate of interest equalisation would be ………..The scheme would be available to all exports made by small and medium scale enterprises across 416 tariff lines.",
    options: ["1  per cent. ", "2 per cent. ", "3 per cent. ", "5 per cent. "],
    answer: "3 per cent. ",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Duty Draw back advances granted against duty drawback entitlements would be eligible for concessional rate of interest and refinance from RBI upto a maximum period of ………..from the date of advance.",
    options: ["45 days ", "60 days ", "90 days ", "180 days "],
    answer: "90 days ",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Export credit insurance is designed to protect exporters from the……………",
    options: [
      " consequences of the payment risks, both political and commercial, and to enable them to expand their overseas business without fear of loss",
      " consequences of the payment risks, both political and commercial",
      "to enable them to expand their overseas business without fear of loss",
      " consequences of the payment risks, both political and commercial, or  to enable them to expand their overseas business without fear of loss",
    ],
    answer:
      " consequences of the payment risks, both political and commercial, and to enable them to expand their overseas business without fear of loss",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "A Line of Credit (LOC) is a financing mechanism through which Exim Bank extends support for………..",
    options: [
      " export of projects,",
      " export of projects, equipment, goods and services from India. ",
      " export of equipment, goods and services from India. ",
      " goods and services from India. ",
    ],
    answer: " export of projects, equipment, goods and services from India. ",
    chapter: 19,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Export credit insurance is designed to protect exporters from the consequences of the payment risks, ………….., and to enable them to expand their overseas business without fear of loss.",
    options: [
      " political Risk ",
      " commercial risk ",
      "both political and commercial",
      "political or commercial risk",
    ],
    answer: "both political and commercial",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Cooperation agreement with MIGA (Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency) an arm of …………..",
    options: ["World Bank", "EXIM Bank ", "Govern ment of India ", "RBI "],
    answer: "World Bank",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The policies issued to exporters and guarantees issued to Banks are ……………..",
    options: [
      "Standard Policies and Specific Policies\n\n",
      "Financial Guarantees\n\n",
      "Special scheme guarantees\n",
      "Standard Policies, Specific Policies, and  Financial Guarantees and Special scheme guarantees\n",
    ],
    answer:
      "Standard Policies, Specific Policies, and  Financial Guarantees and Special scheme guarantees\n",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Risks covered on the LC opening Bank under standard policy is …………………",
    options: [
      "Insolvency of the LC Opening bank.\n.\n",
      "Failure of the LC opening bank to make the payment due within a specified period normally four months from the due date.\n\n",
      " Failure of the LC opening bank to make the payment due within a specified period normally four months from the due date and Insolvency of the LC Opening bank.\n",
      "Non payment risk\n",
    ],
    answer:
      "Failure of the LC opening bank to make the payment due within a specified period normally four months from the due date.\n\n",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Small exporters policy is issued to exporters whose anticipated export turnover for the period of one year does not exceed …………",
    options: ["Rs.25 lacs.", "Rs.50 lacs.", "Rs.100 lacs.", "Rs.250 lacs."],
    answer: "Rs.50 lacs.",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Specific Shipment Policies - Short Term (SSP-ST) provide cover to Indian exporters against commercial and political risks involved in export of goods on short-term credit not exceeding ………",
    options: ["90 days", "180 days", "270 days", "360 days"],
    answer: "180 days",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Turnover policy is a variation of the standard policy for the benefit of large exporters who contribute not less than …………... per annum towards premium",
    options: ["Rs. 5 lacs", "Rs. 10 lacs", "Rs. 15 lacs", "Rs. 20 lacs"],
    answer: "Rs. 10 lacs",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Consignment Policy cover protects the Indian Exporters from possible losses when selling goods to …………………………….",
    options: [
      "ultimate buyers",
      "ultimate buyers agent ",
      "Exporters agent overseas",
      "multiple buyers ",
    ],
    answer: "ultimate buyers",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "As the policy is intended to cover all the shipments that may be made by the exporter in a period of ………..ahead, ECGC will fix the maximum liability under each policy",
    options: ["24 months ", " 12 months ", "36 months ", "60 months "],
    answer: "24 months ",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "On the basis of ………….ECGC will approve the credit limit which is the limit up to which it will pay claim on account of losses arising from default by buyer.",
    options: [
      "credit worthiness of the exporter  ",
      "credit worthiness of the buyer, ",
      "credit worthiness of the overseas bank  ",
      "credit worthiness of the buyer and Bank , ",
    ],
    answer: "credit worthiness of the buyer, ",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under individual post shipment guarantee Risk covered will be protracted default or insolvency of the …………..",
    options: [
      "exporter-client",
      "exporter-agent ",
      "overseas buyer",
      "overseas bank",
    ],
    answer: "exporter-client",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under individual post shipment guarantee Risk covered will be …………….",
    options: ["75 percent ", "67 percent ", "66 percent ", "90 percent "],
    answer: "75 percent ",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under individual post shipment guarantee Premium rate is …………..payable on the highest amount outstanding on any day during the month.",
    options: ["6 paisa", "9 paisa", "12 paisa", "15 paisa"],
    answer: "9 paisa",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Whole Turnover Post-shipment Guarantee Period covered is ………………..",
    options: ["6 months", "9 months", "12 months", "15 months"],
    answer: "12 months",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Whole Turnover Post-shipment Guarantee Percentage Cover varies from ………….per cent in respect of exporters who are Policyholders of ECGC",
    options: ["90-95", "70-75", "50-60", "60-70"],
    answer: "90-95",
    chapter: 20,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "There are  ………………to guarantee",
    options: [
      "two parties",
      "three parties",
      "four  parties",
      "two or three  parties",
    ],
    answer: "three parties",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Banks should avoid giving ……………. guarantees in large amounts and for medium and long-term periods",
    options: ["Secured ", "partially secured ", "unsecured", "zero secured"],
    answer: "unsecured",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Unsecured guarantees on account of any individual constituent should be limited to a reasonable proportion of the ……………..",
    options: [
      "bank's total unsecured guarantees",
      "bank's total secured guarantees",
      "exportrs  total unsecured guarantees",
      "Exporters total secured guarantees",
    ],
    answer: "bank's total unsecured guarantees",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Bank guarantees issued for …………. and above should be signed by two officials jointly",
    options: ["Rs. 50,000", "Rs. 100,000/-", "Rs. 500,000", "Rs. 10,00,000/-"],
    answer: "Rs. 50,000",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "A guarantee should be for a specific purpose and for a definite period, normally not exceeding ………………....",
    options: ["7  years", "8 years", "10 years", "12 years"],
    answer: "10 years",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "AD banks are permitted to approve trade credits for imports into India up to ……...per import transaction for imports permissible under the current Foreign Trade Policy of DGFT with a maturity period up to one year from the date of shipment",
    options: [
      "USD 25 million ",
      "USD 20 million ",
      "USD 15 million ",
      "USD 10 million ",
    ],
    answer: "USD 20 million ",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "General permission has been granted to Authorised Dealer banks to issue guarantees / Letter of Undertaking (LoU) / Letter of Comfort (LoC) in favour of the overseas supplier, bank and financial institution up to USD 20 million per import transaction for a",
    options: ["one year ", "two years ", "three  years", "five years "],
    answer: "one year ",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "AD Category-I banks are now permitted to issue guarantee for amount not exceeding ……………. or its equivalent in favour of a non-resident service provider, on behalf of a resident customer who is a service importer,",
    options: ["USD 100,000", "USD 300,000", "USD 400,000", "USD 500,000"],
    answer: "USD 500,000",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The bid bond guarantee is normally issued for a short period of………... and is terminated on contractor taking up the contract or on the expiry of the contract",
    options: [" 3 to 6 months", " 6-9 months", "  6 months", " 9-12 months"],
    answer: " 3 to 6 months",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the contract is awarded to the contractor he would be required to furnish the guarantee whereby his execution of contract as per the terms and conditions agreed is guaranteed. The value of guarantee should normally be about ………...of contract amount",
    options: ["10-20 percent ", "10 percent ", "20 percent ", "25 percent "],
    answer: "10-20 percent ",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The contract provides that on completion of the contract 95% of the contract amount be paid to the exporter, the balance 5% could be paid to him after a period of say …………",
    options: ["3 months", "6 months", "9 months", " 12 months"],
    answer: "6 months",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The guarantee for payment which has been deferred or postponed for purchase of capital goods like machinery, the necessity to issue …………..",
    options: [
      "counter guarantee ",
      "performsnce gusrsntee ",
      "deferred payment guarantee",
      "security guarantee",
    ],
    answer: "deferred payment guarantee",
    chapter: 21,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The commodity Boards are responsible for …………...of tea, coffee, rubber, spices and tobacco.",
    options: [
      "production, development and export ",
      "production, development and export ",
      "production",
      "production",
      "development and export ",
      "development and export ",
      "export ",
      "export ",
    ],
    answer: "production, development and export ",
    chapter: 22,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Marine Products Export Development Authority is responsible for development of the marine industry with special focus on ………….",
    options: [
      "help fishermen",
      "help fishermen",
      "marine exports",
      "marine exports",
      "adavisory to fishermen ",
      "adavisory to fishermen ",
      "Development fishries ",
      "Development fishries ",
    ],
    answer: "marine exports",
    chapter: 22,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "APEDA provides financial assistance to the registered exporters under its Schemes for ……………..",
    options: [
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, ",
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, ",
      ", Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      "Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      " Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      " Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
    ],
    answer:
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
    chapter: 22,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "India Trade Promotion Organisation (ITPO), is the nodal agency of the Government of India under aegis of Ministry of Commerce and Industry (India) for promoting ……………",
    options: [
      "country's external trade",
      "country's Export trade ",
      "country's export of services",
      "country's Import trade",
    ],
    answer: "country's external trade",
    chapter: 22,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The commodity Boards are responsible for …………...of tea, coffee, rubber, spices and tobacco.",
    options: [
      "production, development and export ",
      "production, development and export ",
      "production",
      "production",
      "development and export ",
      "development and export ",
      "export ",
      "export ",
    ],
    answer: "production, development and export ",
    chapter: 22,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Marine Products Export Development Authority is responsible for development of the marine industry with special focus on ………….",
    options: [
      "help fishermen",
      "help fishermen",
      "marine exports",
      "marine exports",
      "adavisory to fishermen ",
      "adavisory to fishermen ",
      "Development fishries ",
      "Development fishries ",
    ],
    answer: "marine exports",
    chapter: 22,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question:
      "APEDA provides financial assistance to the registered exporters under its Schemes for ……………..",
    options: [
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, ",
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, ",
      ", Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      "Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      " Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
      " Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
    ],
    answer:
      "Market Development, Infrastructure Development, Quality Development, Research and Development and Transport Assistance",
    chapter: 22,
    marks: 1,
  },
  {
    question: "Indian Institute of Foreign Tradeis engaged in ………….",
    options: [
      "Conducting academic courses  of degrees in International Business & Export Management;  Training of personnel in international trade;  Organizing research on issues in foreign trade, marketing research, area surveys, commodity surveys, market surveys; and",
      "Conducting academic courses leading to issue of degrees in International Business & Export Management; and  Training of personnel in international trade \n",
      "Organizing research on issues in foreign trade, marketing research, area surveys, commodity surveys, market surveys; and \n\n",
      "• Dissemination of information arising from its activities relating to research and market studies\n",
    ],
    answer:
      "Conducting academic courses  of degrees in International Business & Export Management;  Training of personnel in international trade;  Organizing research on issues in foreign trade, marketing research, area surveys, commodity surveys, market surveys; and",
    chapter: 22,
    marks: 1,
  },
];
